Hello, Reuben.
Will you come down?
No one will hurt you.
There are plenty of children
to play with.
You do not want to play?
Hello, Reuben.
You want to drive?
Let's go.
Dad mom !..
A CHILD IS WAITING
Hello ... Who? Are you?
Hello. My name is Jean Hansen.
Watch these pearls ... A ...
What? Ge you?
Do? are you from?
From the city.
- Do you have a car ?
- No. I came by taxi.
You do not have one?
Mom and Dad have a car.
I know a boy
that has a Thunderbird.
His p? Re and m? Re have a ...
a Jaguar.
My name is Reuben W? Ddicombe.
You should? Be in class. File.
Ms. Brown, please Reuben
in its class.
You have found? the House.
She is? since God knows when.
Dr. Clark wants to see you.
Here his office.
Dr. Clark is r? Union.
Can he call you back?
Perfect ... Goodbye.
This is Miss Hansen.
Dr. Clark wants to see.
I am ? c? t?
if you need me.
Dr wanted to see you
d? s your arrival? e.
I told you not to come.
But, Doctor ... he's my son.
I told you
it would happen.
Dr. Clark seeks what is
best for you and your son.
This is ? About roses.
I can not plant
if they come pi? tiner.
This is the time id? Al.
Later, they will not grow.
- Emp home to go to the garden.
- Okay, John.
Come in, sit down.
Nothing on your exp? Rience
of infirmi? re.
I do not have any.
Education ?
No I regret.
Music...
You have trained.
I? Studied? the piano.
Have you taught? music ?
Tell me about yourself.
- Cigarette ?
- No thanks.
What would you know?
What pushed you? E? come here.
I do not know where? start.
I went ? new York
for? studying at Julliard.
I wanted to make a quarry? Re
pianist.
I do not t? able.
I did a lot of jobs and ...
I do not know what you know.
Why did you postulated? ?
Why work here?
You need help, right?
The real reason.
I do not know r? Spawn.
Try.
It's personal.
Everything concerning this place
is personal.
Well ... let's just say
I always try to give
a sense ? my life and
up? pr? feels,
I did not r? succeeded.
Think achieve here?
You need help, right?
It must be someone to care
of these children.
Y-you know something?
No clinically, but ...
It is not a matter
an act of charity ?.
It's a work ? full-time.
Few people are qualified? S.
Your r? F? Ences are good.
Mattie appr you? Cie.
R children? Act
? music.
If you want to try,
I let you.
You know the salary?
It does not matter.
$ 50 per week.
Ben Reynolds
in the conference room? ence.
I arrive.
Check Mattie.
She will show you around.
That's all ?
That's all.
Mr. Reynolds?
You? Your Dr. Clark?
O? is it?
In the car.
I gave? v? clothes
? Mrs W? Lson.
We sewed his initials
in pockets.
I hope I'm doing the right thing.
I feel abandoned.
We arr? T? S
on my way.
I pay him? an ice cream.
A double.
It? Was so happy.
He did not know that ...
Mr. Reynolds ...
he knows that? be differ
means.
It will not differ here.
Come ... He waits.
What time is it
when the big hand is on 6
and the small 12?
Six o'clock.
Very good.
And now ?
Tommy?
Six o'clock.
You know this is wrong.
5: 45 pm
or five forty-five.
Yes I do. Six o'clock.
W? Lly?
A quarter to six.
Four hours
or four fifteen hours?
5: 30 pm or 6 pm?
7 am or 7 pm 15?
Seven hours.
8 h 30 h or 8?
8: 30 pm.
To you, Norman.
L? Ve-you.
Miss McDonald, here Miss Hansen.
Enough t? M? Rary
to join? we.
The children here ... Miss Hansen.
Our work table.
We do all sorts of things.
At work.
More questions.
Do what I asked you?
and do it alone.
My name is James and this is Kevin.
We pr? Parons d? J? Thanksgiving.
What is it ?
Doll? E Indian ... That's good.
Find a chair.
L ?, it is our paint shop
fingers. Junius Donny ... ...
And we do ?, basketry.
Crash is tr? S dou ?.
True, Crash?
The most difficult
is to fix their attention.
- You do not sit down?
- Thank you.
We must hold it in? Veil.
Crash, show your shopping cart
? Miss Hansen.
Show him how it's done.
Hello, Miss Hansen.
I give you this basket.
- Is it ... you pla t?
- Um yes.
Continue? work.
Junius, nice work.
Tr? S good, Harold.
- Do? did you get that color?
- I do not know.
Yes. How did you get
the color of the sky?
I do not know.
You have to remember it
If you want r? use.
Purple.
- What color is it ?
- Purple.
How do you get?
How do you get purple?
Red and blue. Exact.
There are only three colors.
Tell me why.
3 What are the colors?
Blue...
Red...
- And the other ?
- Yellow.
Yellow. That's right.
It is tr? S good, Mike.
Do not you drawing?
You do not want today?
Look at me.
You never want to draw.
I want you to me Designed Templates
something. Like that.
Here, try.
Take the brush and draws.
Come on, Reuben.
Draw something.
I want you drawing.
I told you to draw.
All right, Reuben,
leaving the class.
Get out, Reuben.
Goodbye, Reuben.
Louis, Word
are you trying to? write?
Sweater.
How the eye shovels you?
P - U - L - E.
P - U - L - E?
P - U - two L?
P - U - two L. Right.
The next word is "home".
Look at the drawing of the house.
The next word is "chair".
Look at the design of the chair.
Look at the word "chair"
? written under the picture.
Tell me about Miss Hansen.
It it Conna? T in music?
She? Studied? Julliard.
After that ?
Party after 2 years.
She did a lot of things.
For example ?
A shop assistant
of music. Secr? Silence.
She played? in a cabaret
? Brooklyn.
When you met? E ...
It? S riveted.
What do you mean ?
What do we do when
one is 30 and one is single?
It is looking for something
? what to hang up.
And, g? N? Ral,
it is done the wrong fa?.
Let it? the work.
What happened? ? these children?
Want all the reasons?
II is
two hundred sixty-five.
Sammy, do not over so quickly.
The most common,
it was an accident? birth.
Brain insufficient oxygen? N?
or difficult childbirth.
Or if the m? Re has "had the rub? Ole
during the first three months
her pregnancy.
We do not know everything.
And Dr. Clark?
What do you mean ?
Since when is it here?
A little longer than me.
Some ann? Es. What for ?
I was wondering
its ant? c? teeth.
- He asked in the v tres?.
- Oh yes ?
What did he demand? ?
Nothing ... Nothing.
Is it m? Doctor?
He is a psychiatrist.
Warning ? what you do.
His m? Methods have they
? t? v? rifi? es?
No. No m? Method
has? t? r? v actually? rifi? e.
The treatment and the eye education
of these children
are relatively r? cents.
R? Alit ?, what I wanted ...
What I would like to know
if you think it is
he was right
to ask ? Reuben leaving
the class as he did.
Clark id? Es tr? S contest? Es
these children
and what to do
with them.
- Miss Levin?
- Yes ?
You allow me to help you
with your cubes?
Write ... Mom ... Dad ...
It's a Rambler ...
A Nash 1962.
Jimmy ...
My fr? Re just today.
It's sergeant.
My m? Re and my p? Re coming.
Lincoln Continental. 1958.
Two shades of blue.
1956.
Voil? my car.
You are? L? Glove today.
You're going out ? Come.
Have you forgotten? something ?
Hat hat ... ...
Do you want a ride?
Do you love me?
But do
you really love me?
I'm crazy about you.
Come on the road.
Mom, I did? Today.
It is tr? S pretty.
We're taking the city.
Thank you.
Come on, Abe.
I done? Today.
You got a nice suit.
He cir? his shoes.
it'll, little guy?
You've grown. You take
instead of four like!
You look better than your fr? Res.
I will send them here.
I want a hot dog.
A hot dog? And what else?
Enough. Get nothing.
It's your brother? Re, Eric.
Hi, Eric.
Is a? T? wise ?
I wanted to come over sooner,
But I could not.
You can take it
a ride.
Come on, Eric.
Parents come
all journ? e, right?
Yes I do.
Do you t? L? Phone
the m? re Reuben?
II has arrived? something.
She did not come.
His m? Re not coming.
For two years.
He continues ? wait
every Wednesday.
If Willy taught her cat? Chisme,
I would feel so much better.
We tried ?.
Thank you. I do not doubt it.
Good evening.
Good evening, Mr. Tizzelinni.
I just go visit
? Raymond.
He looks better.
Pr? Just me at the first sign
language.
Promised, Mr. Tizzelinni.
Wednesday of the suggestions.
Sometimes I think we better
treat parents.
Ms. Levenson is outside.
She tries to read
a book ? Esther.
She believes that if she reads some
words, it may take him.
Ms. Flaharty ...
This annoys
W? lly does not go? Mass.
Mass !
Willy is unable
to understand a "Ave Maria".
What a circus!
Here is the file. It should not
out of the office, take care of it.
Promised.
Thank you, Mattie.
I must go down.
Raymond Tizzelinni
is covered buttons.
The visits provide buttons
? all the world.
Reuben Widdicombe. Historical.
Premi? Re pregnancy of the m? Re.
A hard pregnancy? Th normal.
Only do? report :
taken by the m? re
extracts thyroid? dians
due to its asth? nie.
Reuben is n?
? the hospital Riverside.
The obstetrician? Was Dr. Kossof.
Normal birth.
Weight ? Birth: 2, 8 kg.
Height: 55 cm.
Family context.
? M re: Sophie. Age: 32 years
Dipl? M? E.
? P re: Ted. Age 35 ands
Dipl? M ?. Architect.
I have to show? A
? any commission.
They will not understand anything.
Functional architecture.
They will understand.
I d? Chirerai all
before they the esquintent.
I know. It's just a town hall
bled in Connecticut.
Growth.
Childhood diseases
chicken pox ? thirteen months
measles ? eighteen months.
How's the big boss?
He has hiccups.
Oh yes ?
Come on, Cossard
l? ve up and trots!
What is the? rattle?
It is too big to play with.
Why do l? Ve not he?
What do you mean ?
The b? B? Ms. De Gaster walk
and it has three months under
Reuben.
You're leaving inqui? Ter? S s a tooth
lot two minutes late?
My fr? Re no market?
that? two years.
It is Pdt
Chamber of Commerce
Galion, Ohio.
This is not an r? F? Rence.
Come on, son, come l ?.
Not so high, Ted.
Look at him. I will pr? Feel
the rear future? re Princeton.
I bring to dinner.
Pr? Pare his high chair,
it can keep us company.
Dr. Maizer ... Yes ...
Please wait.
Dr. Alcorn ...
One moment please.
Reuben W? Ddicombe,
for Dr. Maizer.
- Sit down, please.
- Thank you.
Candy.
Listen, David,
I've d? j? data? two.
Reuben W? Ddicombe.
The doctor expected.
I would like to see the little one,
if you want.
Hello, Reuben. Come on.
We will find you a chair. Come.
What is it ?
Car.
Hand.
How many legs has a dog?
Four.
Here.
Mets? A? its place.
Reuben Widdicombe passed
test Leiter
? the hospital on 5th Avenue,
in pr? sence of Dr. Maizer,
March 6, 1959.
Go out into the yard.
What did he say ?
It is a doctor among others.
He said ...
it is d? cient.
What does he know?
We will see the best
m? doctors. We will fight.
We will fight.
The diagnosis of d? Ciency
was confirmed?
by Dr. Forbes, March 25, 1959,
by Dr. Hargrove, April 12,
by Dr. Yeats, May 4
All recommended? Rent
Reuben f? t plac?
in an institute
for attard? s mental.
On September 6, 59,
Reuben was led by his p? Re
? the Institute Crowthorn.
The Widdicombe divorced rent
in October 59.
Ms. Widdicombe had custody of
Reuben's younger sister, Jennie.
It has since Remari? E
Douglas Benham,
lawyer ? New York.
What cordon bleu.
- Who made the g cake?
- I.
You ? When ?
This morning.
You d? you up early.
This is my sp? Cialit ?.
It is good.
Helen, two hot dogs.
We'll take two Cokes
and? lunch beside the river? re.
If mosquitoes do we
not attack, it will be perfect.
Reuben, get the g? Teau.
File, Reuben.
Reuben became a friend.
It occupies a place? share
in our institute.
This is one of our? Chess
the most spectacular.
it'll in class?
I have not really started ?.
I'm looking for
how to work with them.
As with
all other children.
I r? Fl? Chi ...
Form a band
percussion.
Some children have a nice voice.
Teach them some songs
simple for a show.
Would that seem possible?
I can try.
There is beautiful music
Children.
What is the song
of "Hansel and Gretel"?
"Lullaby of children."
Prokofiev has? Crit superb.
You? Your cal? in music.
Not at all. My wife has? Studied? E.
She works for the institute?
We are s? By? S.
The arm? E mismatched! ..
How? Your you come here?
Named? by the state.
How you? You your int? Ress?
? these children?
It's a long story.
Coke ?
Yes volunteers.
I would like to discuss with you ...
Reuben.
What about ?
Allow me to? Write? his m? re.
Impossible.
I should not myself m? L,
but...
I thought that if someone
communicating with them ...
made them understand that ...
People who have the luggage
parents Reuben ...
You think having
of dipl? my and good incomes
aid ? better understand
a child like these l? ?
You know Mrs. Phillips,
Black Women
who comes to see Junius?
I do not think so
she knows neither read? write.
But no parent includes
she better her child.
I pass? every Wednesday
with Reuben and ...
I know ? which point
a visit to his parents
count for him.
When such a visit
seems profitable,
I organize.
Let's go !
Wait until I call you.
Hyams Harold!
Abe Aarons!
Raymond Tizzelinni!
W? Lly Flaharty!
Junius Phillips!
O? W is Reuben? ddicombe?
Everybody down.
Dr. Clark affect you? E
? another pavilion.
The pavilion D.
Did he say why?
No. He asks you
to go today.
Here Mr. Holland
and Dr. Lombardi, the Congregation? s.
Here is our class
handicrafts.
We do a lot of things there.
I made a.
It's true ?
Seventeen baskets.
He made seventeen.
Here is an example.
Some works are exposed? Es
in the input? e.
What is your name ?
"
His name is Reuben W? Ddicombe.
You do not work ?
Reuben never works.
He does not believe in our m? Methods.
It may? Be right.
His Q.I.?
We do not take into account.
What for ?
I do not believe reliable.
Is it that we have
shown? this ?
Children attach ...
Children tie
these shells.
Sometimes we sell in town.
We'll pick
shells on the beach.
We're all? S
last Sunday.
Who? Are you?
Come, Junius.
My name Holland.
Do you have a car ?
What color ?
Black.
Mr. Holland must visit
other classes.
- What brand ?
A later children.
Mr. Holland ... Doctor ...
Dr. Clark, can you tell us
how many of these children will
lead a normal life?
Children who are here
three wind rel Categories cat?:
the? ducables the am? liorables
and? s counterparts.
Most in the second cat? Gory.
How can lead a life
Normal? What percentage?
What is "normal"?
The normality? is relative.
If they threw us
in a populated world? Einstein,
would we look smart?
How yardstick
does it measure the destiny?
A intelligence or needs?
L? is not the question.
L? is the question, Dr. Lombardi.
You know that the administration
has changed ?.
We love ? we believe? clear? s.
We love ? we think
will do our best for these children.
But the aid application? Standard.
Dr. Clark knows we croulons
in requests for assistance.
Help for blind children ...
Deaf. He knows.
I think these children need
? be helped? s. But n? Very well.
We know what we can
expect these institutes.
We can expect
r? tangible results.
Yes, but Dr. Clark
has only been here six months.
What I r? Proclaims
exactly?
Money
for the qualified personnel ?.
I r? Proclaims the premises.
Waiting list
has 500 children.
We will put them on the roof.
I r? Proclaims workshops
o? most? g? s
will work out.
The question of Mr. Holland
is tr? s relevant.
How many of these children
can you really help?
And how much will end as
l? vegetables, like the little ... Reuben?
I do not believe it ? your "l? vegetables."
And I do not avilirai children
saying how "r? ussiront"
in our soci? t ?.
But they have the right to? Be helped? S.
You do you realize what
State? s think for these children?
- $ 2,700 per year.
- For patient.
It is? Standard. But less compar?
? what? s thinking in roads,
monuments,
in? Leisure facilities.
Damn, it's a disease!
As polio.
And this is not a rare disease.
You go account
five million Am? Ricans
suffer?
Anyone can? Be reached.
Sister of the pr? President has? T ?.
We would like to help these children.
All children.
We have no pr? Jug ?.
In? S your you? R, Dr. Lombardi?
The counselor Conna? T
my feeling.
We conduct a acharn fight?
to survive.
I prefer fetal rerais spend money
toward? for these children
? entered have dinner of the children
Exceptionally dou? s.
Those who become scientists
and g? ned tomorrow.
I know ... I seem not to
have heart, is not it?
But it is my belief.
It is? Emptied you believe everything
what you read in the press.
It's time to go.
Give me the maximum
copies of the budget,
Mr. Goodman.
Willingly.
You know...
I have something? tell you...
I find it wonderful,
your? s dedication to these people.
This is not wonderful.
I like my job,
then I do.
Incongruous reason,
by these days.
I like my job.
Thank you to? Be coming.
I would go around again
your premises.
I accompany you.
Thank you, Dr. Clark.
It was a pleasure.
I'll show you the workshop
o? most work? g? s.
I take my journ? E.
I install? E at the Pavilion D.
Why do I d? do it ?
Sit ... anywhere ?.
There is a pi? Ge? ? avoid:
too attached? one child.
Other risk
to realize
and feel excluded.
There is worse.
The danger for him Reuben-m? Me.
I have often thought? than
if I had a child ?, attard
I pr? f? rerais
seriously ill,
not like Reuben.
Children like Reuben,
borderline cases,
which resemble other
are our worst problem? me.
They are more aware
to? be rejection? s.
His parents refused? the fact
that? was attard?
up? tr? s late.
They permit? play
with normal children ...
put him? the eye school.
Try to imagine the exp? Rience
it has d? ? be for Reuben.
Then they d? Cid? that best
? was hiding it ...
From the prot? Ger.
From the prot? Ger in the world.
Self-m? Me.
Continue this type here
relationship would mean
Reuben would return as soon as you 't ...
- Excuse me.
- What is it ?
? was wrong with Reuben.
What is it ?
He has broken? sound? lectrophone
and toys.
And other toys.
He ate nothing ?.
He refuses to talk.
It is here ?
Send him in.
It works well
because I d? m? nag ?.
I know why he does so.
You're welcome...
Get out, please.
Get out, Miss Hansen.
Sit down.
In veiled fa? Ons to break
your toys! ? has not done here.
And not to eat!
This is not tr? S good,
but I eat myself.
I know you do not Love Me.
But I'll tell you a secret.
I like you.
I know what you Endures.
You do not believe me,
but it's true.
I know that others do to you
die hard and tease you.
But I can not do anything.
You, you can.
Tell me, Reuben.
I beg you, tell me.
Miss Fogarty
Reuben take her to dinner.
Let him go? table,
m? me if he does not eat.
Then no r? Cr? Ation.
He will go to bed
If he continues tomorrow
it will be poor.
Are you well s? R
to act with the best Reuben?
That suggests? Ground you?
How many times
can you cong it? dier?
Email to bed without r? Cr? Ation?
Up? he makes an effort.
There are r? Rules here.
It's Conna? T not.
- He must understand.
- What for ?
Discipline
is part of the life.
M? Me for these children?
Particular surely for these children.
Some freedom? is lost
for Reuben. May? Be? never.
He will find compensation
learning the r? rules.
Living with others allow it
to belong? a whole.
M? Me if he does not want
be part of it?
M? Me if it is never
happy here?
Yes, m? Me so.
Waiting,
I would try to help Reuben.
I am s? R.
Can I? Write? his m? re?
No, Miss Hansen. No way.
Have you so scared
to admit a? failure,
m? me to you?
I think that's it.
W? Ddicombe!
It's for you.
All ?, Sophie ... it's going?
Do? name?
I thought you were? Westhampton.
Yes, I '? Costs.
Reuben ... What is it?
We are in the yard.
No, I do not come.
I do not come point.
Believe what you want,
I do not care.
Yes that's all.
Excuse me.
O? could we find
Miss Hansen?
It is music.
Miss Hansen ...
Ms. Benham?
Follow me, please.
O? is it?
In its flag.
How is he ?
It is well.
Mr Benham ... Here Jennie.
Nice to meet u.
If we wait you out
both ?
It is well?
Why Dr.
Does not he touch? e?
Why have I been able to talk to him?
Ms. Benham,
Reuben is not sick.
This part of my letter
? was a lie.
But c '? Silent? S ...
the only way? Be s? re
you would come.
Doug ...
Go get Dr. Clark
and tell him to come, if you pla? t.
Why have you ceased?
become ?
Do you know
it still awaits
every Wednesday after? s afternoon?
He dressed and waiting for you ...
in the living room.
Ms Hansen, I'll get out.
I busy? E of Reuben.
I know how he feels.
Look, mom,
I design? Mr. Machine.
It is tr? S good.
Make another one.
Why did you give up?
Arr? Tez!
You do not know
what I feel.
You do not know anything.
Excuse me. But I fight
for Reuben.
He can not fight.
You fight for him ...
I fight for him
since his birth.
Since it shows the
? doctors.
All said:
"You can not help it."
I fought my husband.
I fought the m? Doctors ...
and the world for him.
Why give up now?
Do you know what it is
for Reuben and me
to? be together?
To see her child
go crying
because other
were mocked? s him?
Do you know what it is
to hide
when one of the tour?
Do you know what it is to stay
alone in a pi? this with him
and know that if I stay well
alone with him all my life,
one day I will die
and he will go
in an institute.
But it will be too late ...
to adapt.
It is better for him
? be with children like him.
I m? Ri ...
It is my belief.
Tell him, Dr. Clark ...
Tell him ...
? which point
Reuben needed to see.
I do not want her to see him!
I can not see him.
You think
I do not love enough?
But I love her too.
Mom, it's Reuben!
II plays.
Come on, Jennie.
Mom !
Put your tongue against your palate ...
Like this.
No. Against your palate.
At the top ... No ...
Move back your tongue.
Open the mouth. Opens.
Put your tongue on the top ...
Voil? ...
Perfect. Now you try.
Tell me...
Very good. Now stronger.
Morty, this should
? be easy for you.
Withdraw your hand. Look at the map.
Tell me...
Now, put your finger
against my nose. Here ... Sens.
Put it on your nose.
Good. Now tell me :
"mouse" ...
Excellent.
Yours, W? Lly. Look at me...
Look at me.
Tell me...
Good. A little harder.
Very good.
Easy for you, Chris.
One minute.
You're welcome.
Continue the course.
Call the police.
What good is torturing you.
He saved ?.
They have me t? L? Phon? this morning.
If it happened something to him?
It does nothing happen to him.
What we will do ...
it is transferred? rer elsewhere ...
at Devereux.
It is overpriced.
I will manage.
If you went to see?
Are you making fun of him.
? has not co you? terait anything going.
The site must? Be finished
in September.
He saved? !
They are ? his research.
This is you? Gal?
You don '? PROVEN anything for him?
You don '? PROVEN nothing
for him ?
If j? Proves something.
I wish it were dead.
In the lead? S out there,
I thought that? ?to.
I wanted to leave the road.
I would d ?.
It's easy to forget ...
the plans I had for him,
the doctors with whom
I drove,
without believing any of them.
Easy to forget
that I ruin? to find
an r? response, a miracle.
Easy to forget that it's me
who did the only thing? do :
over there on the left?.
My life became a g? Chis,
since that day.
I will arrange the transfer.
I will be going? S out there, if necessary.
Pass me the Crowthorn institute.
Crowthorn, New Jersey.
It was retrouv?
in Braddock Avenue.
One lady port? complaint.
We were calling? S.
Sign here.
It must? Be hard with these kids.
My sister in law was a kid
which is not s? r.
She's ticklish
on the subject.
She put? the hospital.
Do not bother me anymore.
I'm leaving.
I thought I could help Reuben.
I have? T? unable.
I believe...
that we must do? the id? e ...
these children
have no chance ...
no chance.
What were you looking here?
J '? Silent? search
a place ...
o? you might need
from me...
I wanted to help these children.
What do you expect? What for
n '? your not you in music?
Music ?
? is not enough.
So what ?
You do not know
how they feel.
Every Wednesday after? S afternoon ...
they wait.
They wait, that's all.
I do not know !?
The people who work here
do not know how they feel?
Those people who lav? diapers
children seventeen ...
while no cast
a look at them.
Who waited 20 years with them,
and nobody came ...
They do not know !..
But you know...
You and the m? Re Reuben!
Want hatching.
Take the hits? their place !
Breastfeed? your breast!
Give them your love.
It's not enough.
They need them most? A.
But I do not have it.
This is? A ... Run!
Get the hell out of here !
Find good excuses!
But Hear me well.
I could not do anything for Reuben.
Nothing at all. I will not be able
perhaps? never be anything for him.
It will be perhaps? Be
never happy here.
But I prefer f? Re? Chouer fighting
for its dignity? see the rotten
by your love for him.
Come, Miss Hansen ...
Follow me.
Hello doctor.
Here Reuben in 20 years
if we are not careful.
It was the aim? S.
It was the prot? G? S all
up? their coming here.
It was the flavou? S
? shots feelings.
We enferm them? S
in cupboards.
Some have? T? st? Rilis? s.
As st? Rilise the b? Tail.
No one more than they need
r? ussir something.
You will find here
what you want.
It's not that
you can for these children.
But what they can for you.
Sit down, kids.
Let's go.
Sit down, Reuben.
Listen to me.
We will mount a pi? This
on Thanksgiving.
Sit down, Reuben.
This is the story of the first settlers
who have arrived? s here.
There were no cities,
nor houses
and c? was hard,
? because the Indians.
Some of you
will play the Indians
and others will play the settlers.
Crash, will you? Be an Indian?
Yes, I am an Indian.
I am an Indian.
Donald, you'll be an Indian.
You too. And Junius,
a settler.
Yes, I want to? Be a settler.
I am a settler.
You will be a ... Come colon.
We will learn
the 1? re song,
one that opens the pi? this.
I will sing
the first verse alone ...
full ... and then ...
we will resume ...
line by line ...
Okay ? ?gave...
Well, I sing the rst? Re online ...
And you r? P? Tez. Okay ?
All together.
Very good.
If you want to stay
in music,
behave yourself and be careful.
Sit down.
It tries yet again.
Goodman, the Crowthorn institute.
Over here, please.
Thank you to? Be coming.
Can you get out?
Contact us Clark? S my wife
and me about our son.
What I want...
is that someone
takes care of him.
I'll pay whatever it takes.
no need to pay,
apart from a few dollars ...
I mean,
takes care of itself.
I will pay.
I fear
Dr. Clark refuses.
What for ?
II think these children
should help themselves m? my.
This is his m? Method.
We will do out.
It's silly for putting
in an institute.
He must have what he wants.
He needs someone
who takes care of him.
Someone who watches over him
and give him what he? s sire.
Who watches? what to do
What he wants.
Do you think this is the best?
What would be best?
He lives his life
to the fullest ...
like all of us.
He has the brain
a 5 year old child.
The brain is not everything.
Easy to advise parents.
No, it is not easy.
I am a parent.
What? Ge you? ..
I have a daughter 28 years.
And you think
in what Clark?
"We have to accept these children
as they are. That's all."
"Their life has a meaning, a purpose."
What purpose does it, Mr. Goodman?
When Rose is n? E, I thought?
there was no worse trag? die.
We had so many plans.
Everyone turned
he passed in the street.
Rose did not know? Be a trag? Die.
Then the trag? Die
shall? be in us.
In our fa? To cope.
What purpose, Mr. Goodman?
Your son...
could make the plunge ...
or tie packages.
That's all he r? Alisera?
I wonder
we r? Alisons more?
D sol? can not help you.
You're welcome.
Thank you to? Be coming.
I am hungry.
I too am hungry.
The governor said Bradford
there would be? eat
Thanksgiving.
Everything I've eaten? ...
...today...
it is...
a small piece of turkey.
... piece of turkey.
I'm happy
that you have had the turkey.
We ate?
my bread? s.
I would have liked? ...
I know...
Be careful !..
D? P? Che-you.
I would have liked? duck ...
Or goose ... From the goose.
goose or eel ... ...
on this day of Thanksgiving.
We must trust
Governor Bradford.
We have guid? S from the d? But ...
Bring the Indians.
What are you laughing?
These good people will help us
? f? ter Thanksgiving this year? e.
The head Quanto ...
Massasoit ...
and all these good people.
Mom, I have to go
to the bathroom.
Wait.
Voil? Junius.
Look, tr? Sor, voil? your brother? re.
But, Governor,
it's nothing ? eat.
Look what they supply ?.
Fish...
venison ...
From my? S ...
And my? S ...
A goose !
What a great Thanksgiving!
Show them your works.
I made a box.
I made these necklaces.
I made this placemat.
I made this basket.
I did ... I made this plateau.
It was I who décor? Table.
We thank our Indian friends
for giving us the gift of my? s.
We always call
"my? s Indian."
They taught us
? cultivate the seed
Who? cartera? never
famine from our door.
I just tell you about Reuben
and organize the transfer.
As you want.
O? is it?
On the sc? Ne.
This is one of the Indians.
I love autumn ...
fog falls
I love
cr? puscule
the owl that hoots.
C? Was tr? S good, Rose.
Hello dad.
Your hat loses a feather.
We amen ?.
It is in the car.
He is afraid to go out.
Miss Hansen,
could you come here a moment?
Here Mr. and Mrs. Spencer.
Their son is in the car.
Could you go see?
His name is Earl.
You come with me ?
I say no.
Not me.
Do not be afraid. You can come
with me, if you want ...
- How old do you have?
- Eleven years.
Your birthday ?
In fetal next February.
There are beautiful things here.
You'll have fun.
Do you want to come with me ?
Come on ... come, my ch? Ri.
That's ... Come. It's perfect.